RYAN MACEACHERN

Software Developer

CONTACT

778.587.3982

ryan.maceachern.tech@gmail.com

In LinkedIn.com/in/Rmaceac

https://github.com/Rmaceac

Victoria, BC, Canada

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript Rubv

HTML

CSS

Python

Typescript

SOL

Frameworks/Libraries

NodeJS

Three.js

React

EJS

Rails

ERB

jQuery

Bootstrap

Ajax

SASS

Express.js

Testing

Storybook

lest

Cypress

Mocha

Chai

Capybara

Rspec

Systems & Databases

Git + GitHub

PostgreSQL

Firehase

GraphQL

Audio + Visual

Blender

Figma

Lightroom

Da Vinci Resolve

Reaper

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Developer with a background in adventure tourism and finance. I am excited to use my extensive experience in customer service to understand users' challenges and desires in the apps that I develop. I love working in collaborative teams that prioritize educational functions of apps and accessibility of information.

EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPMENT DIPLOMA

Lighthouse Labs

April 2022

ADVENTURE GUIDE DIPLOMA

Thompson Rivers University

2012 - 2014

PROJECTS

SEEK

A daily geolocation game where users test their geography knowledge by guessing the location of unique streetview images. Players can connect with their other players, compare scores and create their own custom games to share with their friends.

Front-End: ReactJS, SCSS Back-End: NodeJS, Express, SQL, Postgres

Front-End: HTML, SCSS

Twilio's API).

Spuddies Food-Ordering Scheduler A scheduler app where the user can place orders with a restaurant and allow SMS create, edit and delete interview

communication between owner and customer appointments.

Back-End: NodeJS, Express, SQL, Postgres

An Javascript application for customers to

regarding the status of the order (using

Front-End: React/S, SCSS Back-End: NodeJS, Express, SQL Testing: Jest, Storybook, Cypress

WORK EXPERIENCE

OWNER/OPERATOR

Blue Sky Bookkeeping - Self-Employed | 2017 - Present

- Working with clients from a dozen different industries to translate what matters most to them and ensure their values are prioritized in the communication and organization of their business finance.
- Built a financially stable business from scratch through self-education, resourcefulness and a constant desire to learn.
- Recently saved a client over \$7,000 in PST charges using my attention to detail to make amendments to their sales tax filings.

HR LEAD & OPERATIONS COORDINATOR

Maple Leaf Adventures | 2019 - 2020

- Filled multiple, extremely dynamic roles that required regular, thoughtful communication with a crew of 50+ employees, ship's crew, engineers and many other employees/clients, each with a different set of values and priorities.
- Solved countless logistical and interpersonal conflicts while ensuring a seamless and unforgettable experience for our guests.
- Spearheaded the company's training sponsorship program in conjunction with WorkBC's Employer Training Grant, processing employee applications and writing grants for a variety of programs.

LEAD KAYAK GUIDE

One Ocean Expeditions | 2018 - 2019

- Led groups of $\sim\!15$ guests with a small team of assistant guides through remote locations on the Antarctic Peninsula while managing safety, logistical and customer experience operations on board the expedition ship.
- Regularly made consequential judgement calls that prioritized the safety of my team and guests, while also providing an incredible experience for our clients.